spreed.com 2016-11-01

# Privacy

Last updated: 11th February 2014

At struktur AG, the creators of Spreed, we respect and protect the privacy of those who use Spreed and visit this website. struktur respects your privacy. struktur will not sell or rent personal information. To demonstrate our commitment to fair information practices, we have adopted leading industry privacy guidelines.

All Spreed products and services (as defined in our Terms and Conditions) are made available subject to this Privacy Policy. When you choose to provide information about yourself, we recognize that you trust us to act in a responsible manner. It is our belief that information provided by you will only be used to provide you with better products and services.

**Collection, processing and use of personal data**  
This website is using the open source tool Piwik. Piwik is collecting non-personally-identifying information such as the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the web), your computer operating system and browser type, language, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. This non-personally-identifying information is only used to analyze overall trends to help us improve our service. The link between this information and your personally identifiable information is never shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

Piwik is using cookies. If you do not wish to have cookies placed on your computer, you should set your browser to refuse cookies before using our website, with the drawback that certain features of Spreed may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

We will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

You can find more information about [Piwik](http://piwik.org/) on their website and in their [Privacy Policy](http://piwik.org/privacy-policy/).

**Spreed Online Meeting Service**  
With respect to this website and Spreed services, struktur will collect, store or use personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address ("your information"), when you voluntarily submit it to us (through the registration page or by using the contact or feedback form). By providing us your information, by accepting our Terms and Conditions, or by continuing to use this website, you are consenting to our use, storage and processing of your information. Personal information submitted to Spreed through this site may be transferred across national boundaries and may be stored and processed in any of the countries in which struktur its affiliates or authorized resellers maintain offices, including, without limitation, Europe. You also acknowledge that the collection, transferring, storage, and processing of  information may be undertaken by trusted vendors of struktur. Such vendors are bound by contract not to use personal information for their own purposes or provide it to any third parties.

We will use your information to respond to requests you may make of us, and from time to time, we may refer to your information to better understand your needs and how we can improve our website, products and services. Any and all uses would comply with applicable laws. We may also use your information to contact you.

**Spreed keeps online meetings secure**  
Business information that is provided by meeting organizers such as meeting schedules, attendee lists, subject matter, invitation texts and content of web presentations, live or recorded, visual or audio and any content uploaded to the Spreed servers are considered strictly confidential and proprietary. We will not view information except as necessary to appropriately support the service. Only on your expicit demand (by switching on recording) Spreed servers will record communication (Audio, Video, Chat, Whiteboard and Questionnaire). As part of the Spreed service, a subscriber may initiate the recording function which will result in the conversation and communications of each user being recorded and logged. All business and real-time information will be deleted immediately on demand of the subscriber or automatically by the Spreed systems 30-days after the information was provided. Any other information transferred by you in connection with your visit to this site ("Other Information" -- i.e., non-business information and information that cannot be used to identify you) may be included in databases owned and maintained solely by struktur or its agents. We retain all rights to these databases and the information contained in them. 

All content uploaded to the Spreed Service is your own private property. We do not sell or release individually identifiable information obtained on-line about our visitors to anyone outside of struktur or trusted vendors of struktur. The only exception to this rule is if we are required by law to release information. Struktur will not share with, sell or transfer any data or personal information provided to us through usage of the Service to any third party without prior and explicit consent.

By making content public on your meeting schedule or profile you give an explicit consent to show the information chosen to the audience specified. Your first name, last name, company, country of origin stored in your own account profile, the title of your published conferences, presentations, and shared files are visible to other users by default. It is your responsibility to ensure that making public that information does not violate their privacy or any other regulations, and only happens when that person has given his explicit consent.

You also agree that the service cannot be used to store, upload, or publish any sensitive information about yourself such as matters of race, ethnic background, religion, philosophical conviction, health, sexuality, labor union membership, criminal offences, social problems and other strictly private issues.

Note according to § 33 BDSG (Federal Data Protection Act): Storing and processing licensee data is carried out by Spreed and neutral service providers commissioned by us in strict accordance with the federal data protection act.

More information is available in our [Security brochure](http://www.spreed.com/eu/help/manuals/index.html/manuals_and_brochures/spreedwebmeeting_information_security.pdf). 

**Online Store**  
Digital River GmbH (element 5) is the seller of the products in our Online Store and your contractual partner. Payment as well as order handling is done by Digital River GmbH, Vogelsanger Straße 78, D-50823 Köln. To process your order, the following information of you will be stored: Email address, first name, last name, address, bank or credit card information. [Terms and Conditions](https://secure.element5.com/esales/termsconditions.html?sessionid=2644003808&random=f9d9613374190546cddf8fdeb01ba8e6) and [Privacy Policy](https://secure.element5.com/esales/privacypolicy.html?sessionid=2644003808&random=f9d9613374190546cddf8fdeb01ba8e6) of Digital River GmbH apply.

**AddThis Bookmarking Service**  
This website contains AddThis plugins which allow you to set bookmarks or share interesting website content. AddThis is using Cookies and processes information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected.

By using the AddThis button you consent to the data processing by Add This LLC according to their agreement.

If you do not wish to use the AddThis bookmarking service, you can opt-out by [clicking here](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out). This will place an opt-out cookie on your computer which tells them not to collect your information for delivering relevant online advertisements. Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

You can find more information about [AddThis](http://www.addthis.com/?r=0) on their website and in their [Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy).

**Changes of our Privacy Policy**  
Last updated: 11th February 2014. We may update our Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised version here, with an updated revision date.

**Right to information**  
In accordance with the German Federal Data Protection Art (BDSG) you have the right to be provided with information free of charge relating to your stored data and, where applicable, a right to have this data amended, blocked or deleted. Please contact us ([privacy@spreed.com](mailto:privacy@spreed.com)) for more information.

**Contact**  
For questions regarding your stored data, please contact us: 

struktur AG, Kronenstr. 22A, 70173 Stuttgart, Germany
